Monkey King, you bastard
孙悟空你这个畜牲
You've promised Buddha
你本来答应如来佛祖
To help the Longevity Monk to get scriptures in the west
护送你师父唐三藏去取西经的
But the King Bull and you decided to eat your master
你竟然跟牛魔王串通要吃你师父
Do you know you've made a real big mistake?
你知不知道犯了弥天大罪啊？
Shut up!
少啰嗦
You've followed me for 3 days
你追了我三天三夜
I didn't beat you up because you're a woman
因为你是女人 我才不杀你
Don't think that I'm afraid of you
不要以为我怕了你
Monkey King
悟空
be polite to Goddess!
你怎么可以这样跟观音姐姐讲话呢？
Shut up
不要吵
You scare me again
你又在吓我
If you're not scared of me
你不是怕我
you needn't hurt Purple Fairy
又为什么要打伤紫霞仙子
and stole her Pandora's Box
抢了她的月光宝盒呢？
You just wanna escape
你不就是想躲开我吗？
Now, I can't escape
既然躲不了
I will fight with you
那老孙就跟你决一死战
What's up?
又干什么？
Don't be angry
大家不要生气
You may violate the rule
生气会犯了嗔戒的
Monkey King, you're so naughty!
悟空 你也太调皮了
I've told you
我跟你说过
not to throw things!
叫你不要乱扔东西 乱扔东西这么做…
Look!
你看！
You've thrown away the stick
我还没说完呢 你把棍子又给扔掉了
Pandora's Box is the treasure
月光宝盒是宝物
You'll pollute the environment
你把它扔掉会染污环境
You'll hurt kids
唉！要是砸着小朋友那怎么办？
If there are no kids
就算没有砸着小朋友
it is bad to hurt plants
砸到那些花花草草也是不对的呀！
What's up?
干什么？
Let go!
放手！
You want?
你想要啊？
Speak up if you want!
悟空 你想要的话你就说话嘛！
Why do you keep silent?
你不说我怎么知道你想要呢？
Although your eyes are full of sincerity
虽然你很有诚意的看着我
I'm very glad, you still have to speak up
可是你还是要跟我说你想要的
Do you really like?
你真的想要吗？
Take it
那你拿去吧
You
难道你真的想要吗？
Damn!
我靠！
Monkey King...
孙悟空…
See
大家看到啦
this guy keeps talking all the time
这个家伙没事就长篇大论
we don't know what he's talking about
婆婆妈妈 叽叽歪歪
He's just like a fly hanging around
就好像整天有一只苍蝇
Sorry, not a fly
对不起 不是一只
It's a swarm of flies flying near your ears
是一堆苍蝇围着你呀
Flying into your brain
飞到你的耳朵里面
Help!
救命啊！
So I catch that fly. Open its belly
所以呢 我就抓住苍蝇 挤破它的肚皮
Take out its intestine
把它的肠子扯出来
Put its intestine around its own neck
再用它的肠子勒着它的脖子
Then I pull the intestine tightly
用力一拉
The tongue comes out
各位 整条舌头都伸出来了
I use a blade and cut!
我再手起刀落
Wow!
哗！
All the people keep silent
整个世界清静了
Now you know why I need to kill
现在大家明白为什么我要杀他
Monkey King, you have so many excuses
悟空 你诸多借口
You don't want to get scriptures in the west
你根本不想去取西经
Shut up please! Beat!
说那么多干什么 打呀！
I've got a super body. You can't hurt me
我老孙有金刚不坏之身
I don't scare of any god
十个观音我都不放在眼里
I'm detroy all devils
今天我要替天行道
Being master I should take the responsibility
徒弟有错 做师父的也有责任
Please let him go!
求姐姐放他一条生路吧！
I have to do so I need to report to Heaven Emperor
我不消灭他 我没法向玉皇大帝交代
Goddess, please tell Heaven Emperor
请姐姐跟玉皇大帝说一声
I can sacrifice my life for him
贫僧愿意一命赔一命
Namonitabhaya...
南无阿弥陀佛…
What did he said?
你到底想说什么啊你？
Give him the pork
给他块肉
Stand by!
大家小心！
A woman is coming in!
外面有个女人要进来
Asst. Master do you think soldiers are coming?
二当家的 你猜会不会是官兵啊？
This is why you're called Blind Bing
怪不得人家叫你是瞎子
Didn't you see Dumby shaking his ass?
你没看见哑巴的屁股扭来扭去的吗？
Do you think he has hemorrhoids?
扭来扭去的说不定是长生痔疮啦
OK, even if he has hemorrhoids
就算是有
he is a soldier with hemorrhoids
也只是个长痔疮的官兵啊
So what to be feared about him?
怕什么？
Who the hell you are?
什么人？
Don't you reckon I'm a woman?
难道各位看不出来我是个女人吗？
What do you come here for?
嘿嘿 你来这里干什么啊？
The world's gone mad
世途险恶 北风凛冽
A weary lady
一个弱小女子
Iooking for a shelter
想找一个栖身之所歇息一下
I wanna brush off the dust of my past
洗洗身上的风尘
Do you know what place it is?
你知不知道这里是什么地方啊？
This is not a nice place You all look gruesome
此地乌烟瘴气 各位又面目狰狞
I don't think it is a decent tavern
绝不像是一家客栈
Is this a slaughter-house?
莫非是一间黑店？
Yes, we are. How dare you come in
明知是黑店你还敢进来
You're in danger already
你不怕送羊入虎口吗？
I'm not sure who's in danger
谁是羊？谁是虎？
I think you're in danger
现在还言之过早
You can be robbers
如果各位大爷是强盗
So can I
难道就不怕我是强盗头吗？
Who the hell you are?
你到底是何方神圣？
Blossom
桃花
Nothing get into my way and survive
桃花过处 寸草不生
Money or your heads
金钱落地 人头不保
Why does Ma'am 30th come to Mt Wuyue?
春三十娘到五岳山来干什么呢？
This devil is a fierce robber
这个女魔头一向是无宝不到
Is here having big business?
难道这里会有大买卖？
Why do you still
你们这些笨蛋
put the money on your head?
还把银子顶在头上干什么？
Put it back!
放下来！
She said it is our head or the money Master
不行啊！金钱落地 人头不保啊 帮主
What are you talking about?
你说什么？
Asst. Master!
二当家
You coward! How can you be my assistant?
你这么没种怎么当我的二当家？
Master, I'm not Asst. Master! I'm Blind Bing!
帮主 我不是二当家 我是瞎子啊
He is Asst. Master
他才是二当家啊！
I will make you regret!
对啊 我才是二当家！
Go away!
你还跑！
Look at yourself Mousing around, so shameful
看看你的德性 鬼鬼祟祟 丢人现眼
How can you follow me around with their hair?
披头散发 人模狗样！
Master, I'm here!
帮主 我在这里啊！
Come out!
还不现身？
Coming
现身了 帮主
Master, you're hit by Kunlun Sage's 7 Ultimate Fists
你中了昆仑三圣的七伤拳
Your wounds are spreading
现在伤势开始发作了
Shut up
你还敢说
you knelt down that time
那天要不是你把脖子缩了一下
and I got hit in the nose
我怎么会被人家打中鼻子？
Master, here!
这边啊 帮主
The 7 Ultimate Fists really hurt Master
七伤拳把帮主害得真惨
Master, I was scared, so I knelt down
帮主 我当时是吓得跪下来嘛
It is heard that people who got hit by the 7 Ultimate Fists
我听说中了七伤拳
will have disease in his eyes
首先是变斗鸡眼
Then he'll become dumb
然后耳朵失聪 听不到声音
After that he can't speak properly
之后声线失控 说话全部都走音
At last, his body explodes and he's dead
最后五脏六腑爆炸 然后就死定了！
Master, there's something wrong with your eyes!
帮主 你斗鸡眼很严重啊！
I am OK!
谁说我斗鸡眼？
I only concentrate my eyesight on a single point
我只是把视力集中在一点
I only change my usual way of vision
以改变我以往对事物的看法！干嘛？
Do you want to take my position?
造谣我不行了 想抢我的位子啊？
No, Master, I don't dare
不敢啊！帮主 不敢啊！
You don't dare? I am gonna kill you!
不敢？我踩死你 不敢！
Kill you!
我踩！
Can you cry out for me?
我踩那么久 就算不痛也随便应付两声嘛
Ah...
收到…
Ok, let's get our weapons and search
好！大家准备家伙去杀…
Ma'am 30th
春三十娘
No need to scare! I'm here!
怕什么！凡事有我！
I'm the leader of the Axe Gang
在下斧头帮帮主
My nickname is Joker
外号玉面飞龙至尊宝
It is nice to meet famous Ma'am 30th
久闻春三十娘大名 如雷贯耳
What are you gonna
请问三十娘驾临敝帮
do here?
有何贵干？
I just wanna stay here for a while
我要在这儿逗留片刻
A while? How long is it?
不知道片刻是多久？
3 full days
两天三夜
Maybe 30 or 50 years
也有可能是三、五、十年
I'll leave when I meet the person
总之等到我要等的人出现
who I want to see
我就会离开
I don't think you can wait so long
我怕你没那么长命
What are you doing?
你干什么？
I've just had a piss!
小完便穿裤子啊
You had a piss here?
你在这里小便？
This is why you have so much water to bath
不然你哪来那么大缸水洗澡？
What are you talking about?
你说什么？
I said live to see that person
我说你没那么长命等到你要见的人
Master...
帮主…
I'm not that easy to kill
想要杀我哪有那么容易？
Ask my brothers first
问过我兄弟们先…
You have no guts...
没义气啊！
You betray me!
你们这群吃里扒外的家伙
God!
天哪！
Kill us all if you can!
你有本事就把我们全杀光！
Forgive me...
饶命呀 女英雄
Stupid! Do you think she will let you go?
白痴！你们以为求她 她就会放过你们吗？
I'm gonna fight
今天说什么也要跟她拼了
even if I lost my life!
听到了没有？
That's fine. Since you're willing to beg me
男儿膝下有黄金！既然他们肯求我
I won't kill you now
那么性命暂时寄存在我这儿
Thanks a lot!...
谢谢女英雄 谢谢女英雄啊！
You...you're so righteous!
至于你嘛…你可真有骨气啊
You're so good!
孺子可教
You all clean your sole and wait for me outside
叫他们把脚底板洗干净在外面等我
Why is there a scar?
怎么会有块疤的？
This is not a scar, it is only dirt
这不是疤 这只是泥巴！
Go clean it
马上把它洗干净
or I'll cut the whole leg off
不然我把它砍掉
Master
帮主啊
why she wanna see our sole?
她为什么看我们脚底板？
It is lucky that you don't wanna see our ass
幸亏只是看脚底板 而不是看屁股
Are you scared?
你怕？
I'm not! You are scared!
是你怕 不是我怕！
Why?
为什么？
You have hemorrhoids
你屁股上长了那么多痱子
She'll say they are not clean enough
说不定她会说你屁股不干净
and cut them off
把它切掉！
Why do you know I have hemorrhoids?
你怎么知道我屁股…
Blind Bing peeped on your shower
瞎子说偷看你洗澡的时候看到的
Why did you peep on me?
你干嘛偷看我洗澡啊？
I not only peeped on you
我不止偷看你一个
I've peeped on you all
所有人我都偷看过了
Why is there so much hair?
怎么会有这么多毛啊？
Sure
正常啊！
I've got more in other parts
我身上其他地方的毛更茂盛
What?
怎么样？
Are you excited now?
是不是看得你心痒痒？
Where did you say has more hair?
你是说你那里长得更茂盛？
No
不是啦！
in fact I only have hair on my head and sole
其实我只有头上跟脚底板有毛
Do you think they grow on the wrong places?
大概是长错地方了
From now on, I'll check all the people
从今天起 我要你不分昼夜
passing here!
查看所有经过这里的人
Check what?
查…查什么？
Check their sole
查看他们的脚底板
If you discover a guy having three birthmarks, tell me
如果发现有三颗痣的 立即通知我
Master! We don't go to rob
帮主啊！我们不是抢劫
but check people's sole
光看人家脚底板
If the others know that they'll say we're perverts
要是被同行知道了 会笑我们变态啊
We can plot against her
明刀明枪斗不过她 暗箭她就难防了
Poison her, make her faint
今晚三更用五毒迷晕香让她尝尝
then rape and kill her!
先奸后杀！
A good plot!
好计谋！
You think so
你也觉得好 是不是啊？
You shall administer the plan
那 这个任务就交给你执行
I don't think I can do this
这么看得起我 算了吧！
I go, no need to kneel down
不用了！帮主 不用下跪啊
I don't want to! I can't control my legs
你以为我想跪啊？是我的腿不听使唤
Master, your wound is expanding
帮主 你七伤拳的伤势越来越严重了
I still have both hands
我还有双手
I won't give up!
我不会屈服的
Master has fallen into a shit pit!
帮主掉粪坑里去了
Master!
帮主！
Have you found the three birthmarks?
你没找到三颗痣吗？
Why does everyone tell me to find the three birthmarks?
为什么每个人都叫我找三颗痣呢？
You can save him when you find them
找到你就可以救他了
What are you talking about?
你说什么？
Where are we?
这里到底是什么地方？
Who?
什么人？
Dreaming
做梦
Did you kill that bitch?
把那个贱人干掉了 是吧？
Spider! Spider...
蜘蛛啊！蜘蛛啊！…
It's only a spider
蜘蛛有什么好大惊小怪的？
It's big
好大一只啊！
How big is it?
能有多大啊？
I've told you to tidy up the place
我早叫你们这些王八蛋平常好好打扫干净嘛
The spiders are bigger than me
现在养出来的蜘蛛比我还大！
What should I do?
怎么办？
It keeps running after me
哇 糟了！这么多人它不追 老是追着我
Maybe I'm handsome
一定又是我的英俊害着我
What?
干什么？
What's up?
什么事啊？
A spider is running after Master?
帮主被蜘蛛追啊？
This way? No...
是不是这边啊？不是…
This way!
这边 这边！
Fine, be quick!
快…！
How come?
哇 有没有搞错啊？
Help!
救命呀！
Come here! I'm here!
来人啦！我在这里呀！
Be quick!
快…！
I'm here!
我在这里！
Help me!
救命啊！
Blind Bing!
瞎子！
Nothing in the front! Turn back, turn back!
前面什么都没有 大家快回头！
No! it's Master! Master...
谁说的 那不是帮主吗？
Isn't it a cockroach?
是吗？没看见啊！
It's Master
前面那是帮主啊
Great! Go!
好！上
You sons of bitches, deceive me
你们哪个王八蛋推我的啊？
Master, I'm coming
帮主 我来救你
What am I touching?
什么东西啊？
Master is saved...
救了帮主了…
Asst. Master is so happy What is he holding?
二当家那么开心 扛着什么东西走啦？
Master, didn't he carry you out?
帮主 他扛的不是你吗？
I'm fine, let's go home...
帮主啊 帮主啊 回家了！
Take a bath, go to bed sooner
待会洗个澡 早点睡
Don't hang around tonight
晚上不要到处乱跑啦
Let go!
哇！
Spider!
帮忙！
Blindy, Help
瞎子 帮忙！
Who?
谁帮呀？
Burn it!
烧它！
Have a rest first
不行了 要休息一下先
Don't let him go...burn it
别让他跑了！
Burn it!
烧它！
No need to be frightened
走开 怕什么呢？
He's there...
在那里呀…
It's over there, go there...
在那边 快追啊…
Here is another
这里还有一只啊？
This one is smaller
这只小一点
Freeze!
还跑？
Where?
在哪儿？哪边？哪去啦？
It's there!
好像在那边
There!
快追！
Only two claws are left Let me break you in half
剩下两只爪子 当中把你给劈开
Go to hell
去死…！
Don't go!
你不要跑
It's here
往这边！
Beat it!
打…！
Give it to me
拿过来
All spread out! Let me burn it!
通通让开！让我来烧死它！
Go to hell!
去死啦！
Burning!
着火了！
Very hot!
烫死我了！
It's Master's voice
怎么好像帮主的声音啊？
Help!
救命呀！
It's Master. Help him!
快救帮主
It's Master
真的是帮主啊！
Help!
救命！
Master, your cock is burning
帮主 你小弟弟着火了！
Be quick
快…
Get the water...
快点拿水来
Put out the fire
救火…
Dying!
完蛋了
Be quick
快点呀！
I'm going to out the fire, too
大家都救火 怎么能少得了我呢？
You can't put out the fire with straw Stay away!
你们拿着 让我来…
Master, it's OK!
帮主 躺下！
I'll put it out!
你别怕啊 让我踩熄它！
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop burning...
踩熄它 踩…
Out you go...!
我踩…
Stop burning!
我用力踩！
I can't take this...
不行了…
The fire is out! Are you OK?
怎么样？舒坦了吧？
You have to step on him and put the fire out
这个灭火呢 一定要这样踩才会灭！
Moron!
这点常识你们都没有吗？
Who burned me?
是谁烧我？
Not me!
不是我啊！
I have no idea
不知道啊！
I know it's you!
我早猜到是你！
I know what you're thinking!
我早就看穿你的心、肝、脾、肺、肾！
You wanna take my place!
你想坐我的位子 对不对？
No...Master...
没有啊 帮主
Master's eyes are Ok
帮主没有斗鸡眼了！
No, I didn't do that
我真的没有啊 帮主！
Master, you've recovered
帮主 你七伤拳全好了耶！
I'm cured! Why?
对啊！为什么？
I know!
我明白了！
You must hurt yourself in order to
治七伤拳的方法就是以毒攻毒
cure the wounds
伤上加伤
It's reasonable!
有道理 有道理！
You have to thank Asst. Master
至于二当家呢 他是无心之失嘛
If he didn't hit you at the crotch
如果不是他踢你小弟弟这两脚
you won't be healed so fast
你伤也不会这么快就治好啦！
Do you have an affair with him?
你这么维护他 是不是跟他有一腿？
I love you so much
人家对你一片痴心嘛
Go to hell! Stop it!
去你的 你发春哪？
I've told you to kill Ma'am 30th
二当家的 叫你杀春三十娘
Have you done that?
你搞定了没有？
Ma'am 30th is a devil!
春三十娘是妖怪啊！
Spider Woman!
蜘蛛精呀！
I'm a rational man
老弟啊 像我这么有理性的人
I can't accept such ridiculous thing!
我怎么可能会接受这么无稽的事情呢？
Kill her!
杀了她！
Master, aren't you scared?
帮主 你就这么去？你不怕？
Of course not! I'm healed
怕什么？我伤都全好了
I will defeat her!
还怕砍不过她？
Great! You have guts!
好！有种！
You said I had guts?
你说有种 是不是啊？
Yes, but forget I'd say that
是啊 就当我没说好了
Master
帮主
You just get into her room and finish her off
那你就随便拿件家伙到她屋子里面乱砍
We'll cover you up!
我在后面掩护你
Why I go first everytime...
为什么每次都是我先…
You said you would cover me up so stay closer
掩护我靠近点行不行啊？
Steady
你放心啦！
we've got weapons
我们这里几十把家伙保护着你
We'll throw them at her
一不对劲就全扔过去啦
You'll kill me, too
那我不是也完蛋了吗？
Don't be silly!
傻瓜！
You won't die, you'll only get hurt!
了不起重伤！要死那么容易啊？
Sons of bitches!
混蛋！
Get! You are not fooling me
起来！你少在我前装蒜
Listen to me
我告诉你
Stop that
少来这一套
Fainted?
真的晕倒了？
Big Cow, Younger Tiger
大牛、二虎
You're all useless. Let me do this
闪得还真快呀！好 我自己来
What?
怎么样？
You faked the fainted?
你刚才真的装昏？
This is a tactic
这招叫做忍辱偷生
It is very useful
大腿捱一刀算得了什么？
Where is the leak?
哪儿漏水呀？
Asst. Master, you're bleeding
二当家 不是漏水 是你流血呀
Don't scare!
不要怕…
I can stop the bleeding
我只要点我曲池 疾宫两个穴道
by myself
血马上就停止
it's not picturesque
这里算不上山明水秀
but it is unique
可是也别有一番风味
You may love this place, eventually
两位住在这里一定会爱上它
Good night!
晚安！
Master...
帮主 怎么样？…
She is a devil!
怎么样？是不是妖怪？
Yes!
是！
She is a real devil!
而且非常的妖！
My heart is pounding!
弄得我心扑通扑通乱跳
Master, stop it!
帮主请留步
You're a righteous man, a hero
师姐说 帮主大仁大义 是侠中之侠
It is my pleasure
能交上帮主你这样的朋友
to be your friend
真是三生有幸
The money put on your bros' heads
今天搁在你们兄弟头上的钱
is all given to you to buy drinks
就当请大家买酒喝吧
Thank you very much, Ma'am 30th
多谢三十娘一番美意
Master, she's not really good-looking
帮主 品味太差了吧？
But I like her!
各有所好嘛
Only thrust the thigh once but there're so many holes
大腿扎一刀 浑身都是洞
What do you mean?
什么意思啊？
Sister, why did you leave?
师姐 怎么突然不辞而别
You ran to this poor village
跑到这穷乡僻壤？
and you're forced to reveal
还被一群大老粗
your real image
用迷药把你弄得原形毕露啊
What are you doing here?
你来干什么？
How about you?
你呢？
I just want to have a walk
我想出来散散心
You're waiting for the Longevity Monk
你是想在这儿等唐三藏出现
you wanna eat his flesh
尝尝他长生不老之肉吧
You can make Granpa Buddha
你能从菩提老祖口中
speak out this top secret
骗他说出这个天机
So do I
难道我就不能吗？
Nonsense!
胡说！
Nonsense? Why did you come to Mt Wuyue?
胡说？那么你跑到五岳山来干什么？
This was called Fingers Mountain in the past
这儿以前叫做五指山
It's the prison for this monkey
是那只死猴子当年被困之地
The top secret says that he'll become human
天机泄漏他会转世为人
and he has three birthmarks on his sole
在投胎之后脚底板会有三颗痣
you can find the Monk if you know where Monkey King is
只要找到他就能找到唐三藏
Sister, do you still think I'm speaking nonsense?
师姐 我这么说不知道算不算胡说啊？
You just want to see that monkey
是你想再看到那只臭猴子吧
You can do nothing even if you see him
再看到那无情无义的人又怎么样
The difference is that he died in Goddess's hands last time
不同的是他上次死在观世音手上
but he died in my hands this time
这一次却会死在我的手上
It will benefit
一个和尚有水喝
only one person
两个和尚没水喝
You know the reason!
这个道理你都不懂？
Do you wanna fight over him with me?
想跟我争
Do you think only you can fake face?
你以为就你会变？
Who?
谁？
Devil...!
妖怪…！
What did you see?
你看到什么？
Nothing
没有
No!
没有？
What are you doing down there?
那你蹲下来干什么？
I wanna tie the lace
我系鞋带
If the secret of the monk leaked
如果唐僧的消息传出去了
I'll kill you
我第一个就把你给杀了
Then, all devils gather at Fingers Mountain
到时候群妖会合五指山
beg for the flesh of the Longevity Monk
向师姐讨块唐僧肉吃都行吧？
Tell the King about this
把唐三藏这个消息报告大王
he will bestow on us
一定重重有赏
Even a bull is talking So many devils here this time
连牛都开口说话了 这次真是百妖群集呀
Go...go away
赶快走…
If I go now, I'm a coward!
这样走太不讲义气了！
No, report to Master
对呀！报告帮主
Master
帮主…
This mountain was called
原来我们这里五岳山
Fingers Mountain in the past
就是以前的五指山
The Longevity Monk and the Monkey King will meet here
唐僧跟孙悟空在这儿会合
My bull is talking
我们牛栏的牛居然开口说话了
Those two things
这两个家伙
one has 8 legs, one's head...
一个有八只手 一个的头头头…
You two haven't slept?
两位还没睡啊？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
ah...
没什么
Two baby pigs are born
我们猪圈的母猪啊 生了两只小猪
One has 8 legs
一只呢有八…八只脚
One has a very heavy head
另外一只头有四百多斤重
Master, we're rich now
帮主 这一下我们发了
We needn't to be robbers anymore...
我们以后不要再做贼了
We didn't rear any pigs
我们哪有养猪啊？
We didn't rear any pigs?
我们没有养猪呀？
Or I'm speaking in my dream!
徒弟有错 做师父的也有责任
Ok, I'm leaving, please take a rest
我走了！我不打扰你们休息了
We're leaving
我们也走了
Walk both girls away
顺便送两位姑娘出去
No!
不行！
I will order someone to search for
两位 明天我一定派相关人等
the guy you wanna see
在这附近彻底搜查你们要找的人
Thank you master
谢谢帮主
Good night! Go!
帮主晚安！走啦
Go! Go!
去！去！
Nothing can be done this time
这下没搞头了
Why does Jing Jing have no reaction
为什么晶晶姑娘对我这个造型
to this image?
完全没反应呢？
Nothing I can do
没办法
Go!
走！
Don't kill me!...Don't kill me!
不要杀我！…不要杀我！
I just wanna have fun with you
我跟你们玩玩的
Do you like playing?
喜欢玩是吧？
Come and have fun
我们就玩吧！
Is it funny?
好不好玩呀？
Yes!
好玩
Ok, let's play again
好玩再玩一次
Play again?
还玩不玩啦？
I don't wanna play...
不玩啦…
You said who's got eight claws?
刚刚谁说看到有八只爪啊？
I can't remember it...
我不记得了…
What?
干嘛？
No!
不要啊！…
My head looks like this?
我的头是不是这样子的？
Yes...! Oh no!
是呀 是呀！
She's not changed yet
是什么呀？她又没有变
Not yet?
这还没变哪？
I'll kill him
一刀杀了他
No
不行
Why?
为什么？
I'm gonna mesmerize him
我要用移魂大法迷住他
he'll be my undercover agent
用他来做我的卧底
Hi!
嗨！
Ghost!
鬼呀！
Go to have a look
过去看看
You said a ghost!
这么英俊潇洒！你说有鬼
Oh dear!
真是没见过世面
Don't be pretentious around here
喏！都老大不小了 还给我装蒜
Or I will cut you into pieces
当心我一块肉一块肉给你割下来
You're so brutal!
不会那么残忍吧？
Look at me!
看着我
Mesmerizing!
移魂大法
Who?
什么人？
It's a long night, no mood to sleep
长夜漫漫 无心睡眠
I thought I am the only one
我以为只有我睡不着觉
But Jing Jing, you're sleepless, too?
原来晶晶姑娘你也睡不着啊？
Yes, why can't you sleep?
是啊！不知道帮主为什么睡不着？
Just because of Jing Jing!
就是因为晶晶姑娘你
Me?
我？
yes, when I saw you
不错！自从看到晶晶姑娘之后
I made up my mind that I wouldn't be a robber
我决定改过自新 不再做贼
I just wanna show my sincerity
为了表示对姑娘你的诚意
I can't face my past
我不要再看见以前的我
Like what you see?
好看吗？
You're monkey?
是你这臭猴子？
Monkey?
臭猴子？
Monkey King
孙悟空
Monkey King?
孙悟空？
You think you're alright with a human face?
你变成人样就行了？
Human Face?
人样？
I have to use Skeleton Fire on you
看来我不用三味白骨火 你是不会承认啦
You gonna burn me again!
哗！还用得着吗？又烧！
Why?
何必呢？
Did I make a mistake?
难道我搞错了？
Why did you use flame bomb to burn me?
哇 干嘛用火焰来烧我啊？
Why did you shave off your beard?
你把胡子剃光干什么？
You're just another guy
你知不知道你少了胡子
without the beard
一点性格都没有啦？
Really?
是吗？
You can't do anything
文也不行 武也不行
Do you want to be a scholar instead of a robber?
你不做山贼 你想做状元哪？
I've thought about this
我有想过啊！
Please stop changing image
省省吧你 改变什么形象啊？
being a robber is
好好的做你山贼这份很有前途
a good job
的职业去吧！
I know
我知道了
I'll try my best!
我一定会继续努力的…
You look like that thing!
什么不好像 像个臭猴子
So pathetic
真失败
Jing Jing loves my violent side
原来晶晶姑娘喜欢粗犷一面的我
Having the personality again
虽然乱了点 不过总算恢复了几分风采
Monkey King, come out!
孙悟空 你给我滚出来
Damn monkey
你个臭猴子
You said you would marry me when I was 18
我十八岁那年你说会来娶我
I have waited for you 3 years
害我白白等了三年
You come out!
你给我滚出来
Our King is not here
我们大王有事出去了
He said give it Miss Pak when you come here
他说白姑娘来的话呢 把这东西还给她
and thanked Miss Pak very much
还说感谢白姑娘的美意
He can't enjoy it
他是无福消受罗
500 years...
五百年了…
We've found the Longevity Monk at last
我终于找到唐三藏的踪迹了
The hair on the sole has shaved off
连脚底板的毛也剃光了
I don't know when it will grow again
不知道要那一年才长得出来哦
Shit! They come first!
糟了！被那两个家伙先到一步！
I have to inform
我菩提老祖一定要想个办法通知
these innocent people
这群无辜的人
You come back to Waterfall Cave again?
你…又回水帘洞来啦？
Waterfall Cave?
什么？水帘洞？
Who are you?
你是谁呀你？
Why do you bring me here?
怎么老是带我到这里来干嘛？
No one brings you here You come here on your own
没有人带你来 是你自己要回来
it is normal to miss your home
一个人离开家久了 总是想回家
Don't tease me!
你不要耍我
My home is at Mt Wuyue
我的家在五岳山第四边一〇一号B1
You have made a mistake can you hear me?
你搞错啦 你听到没有？
Don't annoy me, please!
以后不要再烦我啦 拜托！
We have to go, Master, or we'll be late
出发了帮主 不然就迟到啦
Go? What do you wanna do?
出什么发啊？
Robbery!
抢劫呀 帮主
Who dare to do so?
谁那么大胆 敢抢劫啊？
We go to rob!
我们抢劫人家呀！
Ok, that's fine!
我知道啦 出发！
Go to rob...
抢劫啊…  脚底板…  抢劫啊…
What?
抢劫什么？
Rob the sole
脚底板啊 老爷！
I have no legs. What to do?
我没有脚啊 怎么办啊？
What are you looking at?
看什么看？
Are you jealous of my handsomely shaved face?
脸刮干净了 英俊多啦 妒忌啊？
That's fine
干干净争的很好啊
Yes...
是啊…
Jealous! You guys...
妒忌就妒忌嘛！
Shut up!
还嘴硬！
Grapes?
葡…葡萄？
Master, the grapes are washed
帮主 葡萄已经洗干净了
Go out
出去
The dinner is ready
晚饭已经准备好了
Who?
谁呀？
I'm the grapes that you bring here!
我就是你带回来的那串葡萄
You're grapes?
你就是葡萄？
No, I'm Grandma Ada?
不是！我是菩提老祖
What Grandma Ada?
什么菩你老母？
Stop the non-sense
你占我便宜
I'm Grandpa Buddha, an immortal
我是菩提老祖 我是神仙
I turned myself into grapes and save you
我化为葡萄是来救你的
You stole my grapes and forbid me mentioning Grandma
你偷了我的葡萄 还菩我老母？
Both women are devils
那两个女人是妖怪
If you don't believe me
如果你不相信
you can use my Magic Mirror!
我的照妖镜一照 你就会明白了
I use your Mom's mirror!
我照你老母的妖镜
Say! Listen to me
说         你听我说
Have you stolen my grapes?
你是不是偷了我的葡萄？
No!
我没有啊！
Where are my grapes!
没有？那我的葡萄到哪儿去了？
I'm your grapes!
我就是葡萄啊！
Louder!
大声点
I'm your grapes
我就是你的葡萄
Why aren't you an apple?
为什么你不做苹果？要做葡萄
Listen to me
快说！
You shouldn't think I can't defeat you
你别以为我打不过你
I don't wanna hurt innocent people
我只是不想伤及无辜
Go out!
来呀！
You will be seriously hurt!
我打你这个老葡萄
Jing Jing!
晶晶姑娘
Your beard looks great!
胡子好粗犷啊
Really?
是吗？
Why was it so noisy?
乒呤乓啷什么声音啊？
Just beating the grapes
我刚刚在打一串葡萄
Who're gonna beat grapes?
哪里会有人打葡萄的？
Meal time
吃饭了
That's great!
吃饭好啊
Great?
好是吗？
What a pretty moon. Let'...
我看今天月亮这么美 不如…
Moon? I can't see it
月亮？没有啊？
There is a big moon. Can you see it?
那么大的月亮你都没看到吗？看清楚点
It's not dark yet how come is there a moon?
天还没有黑 那来的月亮
Tell me...
你说…
Who? Who the hell...!
哎 菩什么老母？
Who the hell?
菩什么老母？
I was turned into grapes
我变成葡萄了
Where are you?
你在哪里啊？
In your trousers
我在你的裤裆里面
Big grapes!
哇！这么大一坨？
It's yours. I'm at your back!
那坨是你的 我在你后面
That's great to see you
再见到你太好了
You trust me now!
你现在相信啦？
Yes, I trust you
我相信了 相信了
Why do we have devil here?
我这里怎么会有妖怪出现呢？
Stupid fool, listen to me
笨蛋 我告诉你吧！
These devils are waiting for the Longevity Monk
这群妖怪是等唐三藏重现人间
Longevity Monk?
唐三藏重现人间？
500 years ago Monkey King was destroyed by Goddess
五百年前孙悟空被观音大世所消灭
His master Longevity Monk wanted to save him
他师父唐三藏为了救他
He exchanged the monkey's life
用自己的性命
with his own
换取孙悟空一次重生的机会
He hoped this monkey would be good
希望这只猴子能改邪归正
Why does the Longevity Monk
唐三藏为什么在这里出现
need to appear?
你还没告诉我？
he wanted to save the whole world
不错！唐三藏当年为了普渡众生
so he went to India and tried to get scriptures
不怕千辛万苦去取西经
he hoped they would do good to the people
希望借此经书来感化世人
All devils were impressed by his spirit
满天神佛都被他这种精神所感动
heaven Emperor saw that
玉皇大帝眼见如此
He gave the monkey a chance to revive
因此给孙悟空一个机会转世
He planned the master and the disciple to meet here
安排他们师徒今世在这儿重逢
Then they can finish the journey to the west
继续去完成取西经的使命
Now, you know why there are so many devils here
为什么那么多妖怪在这儿出现
You got it
你明白啦？
So I am having the same
怪不得我长久以来都在做同样的
dream
一个恶梦
In a pitch-dark area
在一遍漆黑孤独的环境里面
a pair of seductive eyes
一对一对非常色迷迷的眼睛
Iooking at me
一直盯着我看
make me embarrassed
看得我都非常不好意思
Your eyes look like the eyes in my dream
就是你这种眼神
Sometimes, my face becomes red
有好几次还盯得我脸都红了
I have to face the devils tonight!
原来注定我今天撞妖！
Yes! You are facing devils tonight!
对呀！你今天真的撞妖了
Two Magic Bags here and some invisible stickers
这两个乾坤袋 一沓子隐身符
You're invisible if you stick one on your body
你把符贴在身上 她们就看不到你了
Cover him by it when he is not aware
趁她们不注意 你就套在她们头上
I'll cover you up from the back
去吧！我在后面掩护你
This is my line!
你这个对白平常是我说的诶
Whom are you talking to?
你跟谁说的？
To him
跟他
Let me help you!
对啊！我当然帮你啊
That's great! You're my good bro
了不起！不愧是我的好哥们
Tell all bros to come in
你现在出去叫所有兄弟进来
give a magic sticker to each of them
每个人给一道符
I go back to get the Magic Bag
我回菩提老祖那儿拿乾坤袋来
Then we can catch all the devils
我们一起抓妖怪
No problem
没问题
Good brother
好哥们
Your eyes today...
你今天眼神怎么…
Are they seductive?
淫荡吗？
Yes
对啊
I will help you
我一定帮你的
Help yourself!
两位 请慢用啊
What to do?
这怎么办？
It is Master's order
我也没有办法 是帮主吩咐的
You wait a moment
那你也得想个办法啊
Asst. Master
二当家
Tell the others, Master is looking for us
通知其他人 帮主找我们
Go
快去…
Invisible sticker
隐身符
Go...
走吧…
Sister
师姐
OK...
知道了
Let's keep quiet and see what they want
我们不动声色 看他们干什么
Sister, drink!
师妹 喝酒啊！
Sister, you drink too
师姐 你也喝啊
What are you doing?
你怎么啦？
I'm drunk. I wanna sleep
我有点醉 我想睡一下
don't be afraid. We're invisible
不用怕 看不到的
You shouldn't drink so much if you cannot drink
不能喝就别喝嘛 真是丢人
We're invisible
真的看不到诶
You can see nothing all the time
本来就看不到
Ok!
走
Master hasn't come yet
怪了 帮主怎么还没来呀？
Yes
就是
You say there is roast chicken
不是说有烤鸡吗？
Master! It's burning
帮主 着火啦！
Don't be naked
不能脱
Pay me back! Fool!
快还钱哪 混球！
No need to be like that?
你说就说 干什么那么凶呀？
None of your business, pay me back
我凶不行啊？借了钱不用还的啊？
When did I borrow money from you
你放屁 我什么时候跟你借了
You owe me
是你欠我钱？
I owe you?
我欠你？
Don't you remember?
怎么？不记得了吧？
No...
对啊！
You lost your memory
没记性
Sorry
对不起呀
You should pay back!
妈的！现在该你还钱啦
/No need to be like that
喂！你用得着这么凶吗？
Pay me back, or I'll ruin your face
不还钱我毁你容啊！
I have paid you back last month
我上个月不是已经还你了吗？
Really? Yes, yes
还了？对对对 已经还了！
You're old. You lost your memory
你老了 记忆力衰退了
Forget it, it's my fault
算了 刚刚是我先不对嘛
Cut it! Cut it!
割了吧 都烧焦了！
That's better than nothing
脆了点！总比没有好
Fight with him! Bros!
明刀明枪跟她们拼了
Bros, let's go!
兄弟们 现身
Yes!
是
Devils, come out!
两只妖怪 出来受死吧！
Where is the Magic Bag?
我的乾坤袋到哪里去了？
The Magic Bag is here They wanna frame you
乾坤袋在这里！主人 他们想害你
Traitor, you betray me
反间谍 你敢出卖我们？
Today, you betray me
不过他今天能出卖我
I will betray you one day
明天也能够出卖你们
Really?
是吗？
Yes!
是啊！
I want to destroy all devils
我菩提老祖为了伏妖除魔
I can take off my underwear!
三角裤都脱了
Master, there's really something wrong with Asst. Master
帮主果然有眼光 二当家的真的有问题
That guy is unwilling to do anything even if I beg him
这老小子平常叫他做事 推三阻四
Now, he admit so quickly There must be something wrong
这次这么爽快 一定有问题
Pull him out
把他拖出来
Yes!
是！
Let me go...
放开我
Shut up
少啰嗦
Kneel down
跪下
You son of a bitch I'm gonna kill you tonight
你这叛徒 今天晚上就把你烧来烤着吃
Fine!
好！
You can't blame him
这也不能怪他
He's only mesmerized by both devils
他只不过是中了两个妖女的移魂大法了
Let me go
放了我！
or I'll tell my Master to kill you
不然我叫我的主人杀了你们
Shut up!
你还敢多嘴！
Wong Choi
旺财
The string you're biting is so familiar
你咬的这根绳子我怎么觉得好面熟啊？
Stranger
奇怪
It is the string for my Magic Bag
就是我绑乾坤袋的绳子啊
Son of a bitch
死老头
How dare you come here!
天堂有路你不走 地狱无门你闯进来
Come here!
来吧！
I'll kill you, reincarnated Monkey King
让我掐死这个托世孙悟空
Then you won't find the Longevity Monk
你就永远都找不到唐三藏了
What?
什么？
He is the Monkey King?
他是孙悟空？
Say you're the Monkey King
你要暂时冒充啊
or we'll all die
不然我们就完蛋去了
He's not the Monkey King
他不是孙悟空
He can't even withstand my Skeleton Fire
他连我三味白骨火都受不了
He is not the Monkey King?
怎么会是孙悟空呢？
Shit!
玩笑开大了吧？
You've exposed a top secret
这种天机你也敢泄露出来？
Really?
你秀逗了？
This way
这一边
Are you really a fairy?
你算是一个神仙吗你
Give me your hand
快把手拿过来
It is too much of you...
过份…
Do you think I can't withstand your Skeleton Fire?
你以为我真的怕你的三味白骨火吗？
Burn me again
你再烧一次试试看
Serious?
来真的？
Great!
好哇！
I'm not scared! See?
我不怕啦！对不对呀？
Yes!
对啊！
You can burn my hand if you like
我孙悟空就一直把手放在这里让你烧
I'm not afraid of you
让他们见识 见识！
Not burn my hand?
不就是烧手吗？
Burning
焦了
The hand is still OK
真的烧焦了也没有事
Let go!
放手！
Now you know I'm great
你现在知道我是真的啦
Surrender!
快点投降
I have got my bros and a fairy
我还有一帮兄弟 再加上个神仙
Where are you going?
诶 你到哪里去了呀？
I'll take revenge on you one day
我改天帮你报仇
Even a fairy is not righteous
我靠！神仙都不讲义气
No need to ask
那不用说了
My bros must be there
我那帮兄弟一定都站到那边去了
Yes! Master!
是啊 帮主！
Sons of bitches!
唉！一群大白痴
Are you that heartless guy?
你就是那个负心人？
You deceived me last night!
昨天晚上你还骗我！
That Monkey King
可恶的臭猴子
Sister will not be married just because of you
我师妹嫁不出去就是因为你
Me?
我？
Get the Joker!
抓住至尊宝！
Go!
上！
Stop that
不要乱来！
Master, go
帮主快跑
Don't kill my bros!
不要杀我的兄弟呀
Master
帮主
Blindy, I'm here, no need to scare
瞎子 不用怕 有我在
Sorry, Blindy!
对不起啊 瞎子！
You have made a mistake
计算错误少走了一步
You won't blame me, will you?
你不会怪我吧？
For my whole life I know
我一辈子…         我知道
I'm blind...
都是个瞎子
But I am right to be your follower!
我最有眼光就是跟着帮主
Kill you!
我跟你们拼了
You go to hell
去死吧你
You can't kill him
不能杀负心人
You still help him
你还帮着他
You want to rely on him to find the Longevity Monk
还要靠他找唐僧呢
Take him back to Spider's Web Cave
带他回盘丝洞
Sister
师姐
Only one man can be benefit by it
一个和尚有水喝 两个和尚没水喝
You don't know this in fact
这个道理原来你不懂啊
You won't gian anything even if you hurt me
你打伤我 也不见得一定有水喝
Look at your palm
你自己看看手掌
Black Widow!
黑寡妇
You've been poisoned by my weapon
你中了我的盘丝软夹毒
You will die in 7 days
七天之内没有我的解药
if you can't get my remedy
你就会毒气攻心而死
Sister, I don't dare to do so anymore
师姐 我再也不敢了
Get lost!
滚开！
You regret at last
终于良心发现了你
No! A fierce thing has come
不是啊！外面来了个更狠的
Go out and have a look
出去看看
Where are you going?
你们上哪去？
No!...
别去啊
King Bull has come?
牛魔王也来了？
King Bull?
牛魔王？
Pretend to be dead here?
你也装死啊？
Me too...
我也是
Monster
快跑
Granpa Buddha
菩提老祖
Give the Longevity Monk to me
今天不把唐三藏交出来
or you're gonna die
死路一条
We have nothing to talk
少废话！
You are looking for the Monkey King
你问托世孙悟空嘛
My bro Monkey King?
我结拜老弟孙悟空？
Where is he?
在哪儿？
This monster
这个更狠的
is the Monkey King's Bro
原来是孙悟空的结拜大哥
We are saved
这次有救了
I'm you Bro
小弟就是结拜大哥你的
the reincamated Monkey King
结拜弟弟孙悟空托世
You?
是你？
Yes...
是…
Yes! It's me
正是小弟
I'm gonna kill you adulterer!
我杀了你这个勾引二嫂的王八蛋！
Tell me your name, witch!
何方妖女！报上名来
I'm Boney M of Spider Devil
盘丝大仙座下大弟子白骨精
Spider Woman
蜘蛛精
In the old days when I know your masters
我认识你们祖师盘丝大仙的时候
where were you?
你们两个还不知道在哪儿呢？
I have no business with you...
今天居然敢跟我放肆
Change...
变…
I'm going to kill
今天有谁敢挡我
the ones who black my way
我就杀了谁
Try my White Bone Whip!
尝尝我的白骨鞭！
Change!
变
Dragon Heavenly Silk!
神龙盘丝
Go!
快走！
It's only small trick
雕虫小技
Blindy, you're still alive!
瞎子 你不是死了吗？
We are in trouble
我们刚刚是装死的
I admire you
我靠 我服了你
Don't go...
不要走呀…
Let me see what magic you have got
看看你们还有什么法宝？
King Bull Go
死牛魔王         走
My Little Buddha in hurt
他打伤了我菩提根
Another hundred years before it is healed
起码得练上百八十年才能跟他斗了
Get up
起床了！
What are you doing?
你干什么？
Master wanna see you
我主人要见你
What place is this?
这是什么地方？
Spider Web Cave
盘丝洞
Spider Web Cave?
盘丝洞？
Yes!
对呀！
I'm Spider Devil's disciple Spider Woman
我主人是盘丝大仙座下大弟子蜘蛛精
This is Spider Web Cave
这里不是盘丝洞是什么？
Spider Web Cave?
盘丝洞？
Let's go! Monkey
走吧 臭猴子！
Hey, you have gone mad
你疯啦
I'm your Master, monkey!
我是你的帮主啊 臭猴子！
I'm mad
我是疯了
You are lying!
可是你还在装傻
You've admitted that
在山寨你已经承认
you're the Monkey King
自己是齐天大圣了嘛
Go!
走吧
Get smart just for once
你聪明一点
I was forced to pretend
我是被迫暂时装的
you can use the Magic Mirror to show my true identity
不相信你拿个照妖镜看看我是不是？
Magic Mirror?
照妖境？
Can you see it?
看到了吧 看到了没有？
Yes
不是！
Clear?
清楚吗？
Deceive me!
骗我！
This is not the Magic Mirror
这根本就是…
Pig!
猪啊！
Sister, have pity on me
姐姐 你可怜可怜我吧
Stay calm
你急什么
I guarantee that you can trust
在这段时间里只要你乖乖的听话
my word this time
我保证你没事
Master!
主人！
Master! The monkey has come
主人啊！臭猴子来了
Where is the Longevity Monk?
臭猴子！唐三藏到底在哪里？
Big misunderstanding, everybody
这个误会好大呀 各位！
How big?
这个误会大到…
Let me tell you secretly
我要偷偷地跟你们说
I was born in the Year of Monkey but I'm not the Monkey King
我虽然属猴 可是我不是臭猴子！
A waste of time!
多说无益！
I have got the Magic Mirror and everything
我照妖镜也有 什么都有
You can use the mirror on me
你自己来照照我看是不是
Fake mirror
假的 假的
how dare you use the fake mirror...
假的你也让我照一照啊
Now! Stop playing game
你不要再装蒜啦
If I'm the Monkey King
如果我真的是孙悟空的话
why am I standing here for you to bite my hand?
就不会在这边被你们耍了
I could jump to the sky
我一个跟斗飞上天
Then shit on your heads
然后在你们天灵盖拉一堆屎
You haven't changed to be Monkey King yet
你还没变身呢
You'll shit at that time
到时候你以为你不拉
What is it, sister?
师妹
Broken hearted?
心疼啦？
No
没有
No?
没有？
I won't be hurt by this man again
我不会再为这个男人心疼
you are lying to me!
你骗我！
Sister, I'm not lying to you
我真的没有骗你
Then kill him
没骗我的话 你一剑把他杀了
Kill him
把他杀了？
Don't you want to find the Longevity Monk?
你不想找唐僧了吗？
Yes! But I don't think you will kill him
想啊！可是我不信你会一剑杀了他
Not accurate...
猪嘴巴…
Give the sword!
把剑给她！
Give! Understand
给她！
Kill him!
杀他！
You've sliced a piece of my thigh out
你割到我大腿啦
I intended to do that
我故意的
Give me a bill and I'll pay you back
那你要赔我医药费呀？
You're welcome
少来
I kill you!
我是要杀你！
Cheap whore, you still love that monkey
贱人 我早知道你对臭猴子余情未了
Stop that, I'm gonna kill you
废话少说 拿命来！
Are you Ok?
你要不要紧？
You're still concerned about me
在危险时刻还这么关心我
I'm gonna love forever onwards
从现在开始 爱你一万年
They are outside
我靠 在外面
Can this door block them?
这门安全不安全哪？
this door is mad of unbreakable steel
这门是祖师爷用万年金刚石做的
Stand aside
你怎么了？       你走开
Sister, do you remember how he treated you in the past?
师妹 你不记得他以前怎么对你啦？
He deceived you, refused to marry you
他欺骗感情 背弃婚约
You had a good marriage with Chilian Immortal
原来你跟赤炼君有段美好的姻缘
He ruined it
都被他搅和啦
He can do nothing now
他现在还没本事
When he returned to his own image
等他回复真身之后
he'll leave you
一样不会理你的
Have you finished? Son of bitch!
你他妈的有完没完？
Damn monkey how dare you call me a bitch!
臭猴子 你敢骂我！
Scold me, son of a bitch
我就骂你怎么样？
Don't think it's safe to hide inside
你别以为躲在里面很安全
it's full moon tonight
今天是十五月圆之夜
She will become a zombie!
到时候她尸变 你死得难看
I don't scare, son of a bitch
我靠 我是吓大的啊？
What?
什么？
There are many hills and caves here
大王 这里有几千个山 山洞又多
We don't know where the Spider Web Cave is?
不知道哪个才是盘丝洞的入口啊？
Yes...
是啊…
More than the bugs in my body. Search!
是吗？比我身上的牛虱还多？给我找！
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
How about inside? Are you fine?
里面怎么样？死了没有啊？
Of course I'm alright
你死了我们都不会死
We are very happy
我们是快乐得不得了
Jing Jing is till very pretty
晶晶姑娘美得一塌糊涂
I'm still very handsome
我是帅得乱七八糟
We are still very good-looking
我俩是俊男美女
Meal time, Ma'am 30th
吃饭了三十娘
Help...
救命啊
Zombie!
尸变了
Open the door!
开门
I can't open it!
开不了呀
Kiss her, breath life to her
嘴对嘴过点阳气给她
Maybe it will be stopped
这样子可以阻止她一下
Scare me!
吓死我了！
Sister, you can't defeat me
师妹 你斗不过我的
Really?
是吗？
I'll break you neck if you move
你动一下我就扭断你的脖子
Give me the key! Lock him up
快拿钥匙！把她关进去
You wanna go inside
你这么爱进去 是不是？
Now you can go
进去！
Goodbye!
再见！
Please stop taking revenge
冤冤相报何时了
Listen to my suggestions
我有个很好的建议
You can beat me but please don't hit my face...
先说好 不准打脸
Stop beat my cock, thanks
那里都别打啊 拜托！
There is a chicken, Ma'am 30th
还有只鸡啊 三十娘
I'm telling you
我叫你跑…
No reactions after a kiss
这样子亲她 她都没反应啊
Don't lock it up
不要锁
Ok, since you refuse to open the door
好！还不开门是吧？
I warn you
我警告你啊
I'll rape and kill your lover
我把你的心上人先奸后杀
One
一
Two
二
I get it
中
Three
三
Seductive magic
催情大法
Go!
走哇…
What are you doing?
你干什么？
I have just shivered for a while
我打了个冷颤
Very interesting
好过瘾啊
You shivered on my body?
你在我身上打了个冷颤？
Yes
是啊
Oh god!
我的天啊！
It must be better if she's not a devil!
如果不是妖怪那有多好！
You're poisoned
你中的毒越来越深
You'll die if you don't cured
再不解 会死的
What for even if I'm cured?
解了又怎样？
Living long is meaningless if you are unhappy
不开心 长生不死也没用
Your last few days will be great if you're happy
开心 就算只能活几天也已足够
If I tell you I'm the Monkey King
如果我告诉你我不是孙悟空
what do you think?
你会怎么样？
I will kill you
我会杀了你
I'm not him
我真的不是孙悟空
This is a magic mirror
这块真的是照妖镜
You should use it
你照照看就知道了
You're not him, really?
什么？你不是他？
I'm not
不是
Don't you scare that I will kill you?
你不怕我杀了你吗？
Yes, but I have no option
怕！不过没办法
Because I don't want you to look at me
因为我不希望你看到我的时候
while you're thinking of another
心里面却想着另外一个人
I would like to kill you
我把你给杀了
You said living long was meaningless
来吧！就像你说的 做人不开心
if you were unhappy
就算长生不死也没有用
Go ahead!
来吧！
Yes, I'll
来就来！
Shit! Who make this knot?
他母亲的 是谁绑的？那么紧！
Let me do it!
我来解！
Sorry, I don't mean it
对不起 我不是故意的
You do it strongly
我是看你那么冲动
So I wanna do it with you
配合你一下而已！
Although I'm not a righteous man
我虽然不是什么正人君子
I won't take advantages from the others
但也不至于乘人之危
I'm not used to do it at daytime
白天我不习惯
Let's wait till night
晚上再说
No matter when
晚上也好 白天也好
call me if you need me
你随时需要 随时吩咐
From now on
从今天开始
I'll be with you
我会一直陪着你
Can you get him?
找到没有？
No
没有
Go on
继续找
Damn!
老天瞎了眼
I'm so pretty
我春三十娘貌美如花
But I have a baby with such an ugly man
居然跟这么丑的男人有了
Ma'am 30th
三十娘
Shut up!
你闭嘴！
I will kill you if I'm not pregnant
要不是为肚子 我早就打死你
Thanks
谢谢
Why are you so happy?
你那么开心干什么？
Tell you...
我警告你…
Don't tell the baby
将来他长大了
you're his father
你不许承认你是他的…那个
What should I be?
那我算什么？
His maiden
奶妈！
I'm a man. I can't be a maiden!
我是男人怎么做奶妈啊？
We bring him up
孩子是我们带大的
He don't know if a maiden is a man or woman
你不说 他怎么知道男人不能做奶妈？
That's right
那倒也是
I've found a guy just like you
我找到一个很像你的人
It's you?
是你？
Do you wanna know where the Longevity Monk is?
想不想知道唐三藏在哪里？
Yes, I do
想
Don't strike back if you do
想就别还手
you have to pay for the flesh of the Longevity Monk
要吃唐僧肉总要付出一点代价
It worths!
值得！
If you give me the medication for Jing Jing
如果你肯给我解药救白晶晶的话
I will tell you where the Longevity Monk is
我就告诉你唐僧在哪里
You just do it for that bitch
又是为了那个贱人
I like to do so
不爽呀？
Maiden
奶妈
Maiden is kissing you
奶妈疼你啊
Ok, let's go by tomorrow
我爽了 明天出发吧
Because of love
为了爱情
you can ruin my face if you like
就算你真的毁我容 也是值得的
Hurry up, do you wanna save someone?
快点哪 你到底救不救人哪？
Just let me do it!
你让我上马…
Joker
至尊宝
Sister can't take this anymore You go ahead!
你再不快点 师妹就不行了
Let me...do that
你得让我上马才行呀
Not here
不见了
Everyone deceives me
全都是骗我
We'll reach the Buddha Cave after climbing this hill
过了这座山就回到菩提洞了
No, Ah!
不要啊 啊…
Jing Jing!
晶晶！
She thought I left her alone
一定以为我丢下她不管了
How long will you search?
还要找多久？
Jing Jing
晶晶
She's poisoned, must have died and fell down from the cliff
毒发滚下山咯！
It's all because of you
讨厌 就是因为你
You shouldn't let me sleep for a whole night
为什么让我睡一个晚上？
I should come here as soon as possible
不连夜赶来
You should whip the horse strongly
你为什么不快马加鞭？
We can be faster!
我一定跟得上
I won't tell you where the Longevity Monk is
你别希望我把唐僧的事情告诉你
I don't know anything
我什么都不知道
How dare you put the blame on me!
你自己走得慢还怪我？
What?
什么？
We discovered that Boney M fainted under the cliff
大王 我们发现白晶晶昏倒山崖
Granpa Buddha has died
菩提老祖重伤不治
God is helping me!
天助我也！
Go in!
进去！
If you don't tell me
你不说出来
you can't go out
一辈子都别指望出去
I won't listen to you
懒得理你
The ground is not so hard
地也不是那么硬 有办法！
Powerful devil, extraordinary energy!
盖世魔王 神功护体
I will cure your wound but
我把你伤治好
you must take me to the Cave to get the incarnated monkey
你要带我去盘丝洞找托世的猴子
We'll find the Longevity Monk sooner or later
我就可以找到唐僧
You can also eat the flesh of the Longevity Monk
到时候吃唐僧肉少不了你的份
or you will die painfully
否则我要你死得比现在痛苦十倍
I have to come out even if I have to dig a tunnel
挖隧道也要离开这里
I can move freely in time and space with the power of moon
借助月亮光华可以穿梭时空
What is it?
什么东西呀？
This is the Indian language
般若波罗蜜？是梵文啊
The Pandora's Box
月光宝盒
The treasure left behind by Spider Web Devil?
盘丝大仙留下来的宝物？
Take me into the Cave
快带我进盘丝洞
Why does the belly feel painful?
怎么肚子有点疼？
Is it coming?
是不是要生啦？
Where am I?
把我转哪里去了？
Why so many traps?
这么多机关？
It becomes wetter and wetter
越走越湿！
Welcome, our King!
大王 你回来了？
Damn! I've met a ghost!
撞鬼啦我
What's going on?
你装成这个样子干什么嘛？
You love the Longevity Monk
你喜欢唐三藏
so I play him to make you happy
我扮成他让你开心嘛
What are you doing?
你干什么嘛？
I'm helping you to give birth!
我帮你接生啊
The head is coming out!
头出来了
Really, I've no feeling
是吗？我怎么没感觉呀？
You see?
你看啊？
This is my knee
那是我的菠萝盖呀！
So there is no hair
怪不得没有头发
Someone's coming
有人来了
Hide up, be quick
先躲一躲 躲一躲！
I'm hurt
好痛啊
I'm hurt, too
我也好痛啊
Please let go of your hand! Alright!
求求你把手放开 好不好啊？
Goddess
观世音
Monkey King you'd committed serious offences
孙悟空 你当年罪恶滔天
I hope you know you're wrong
希望你今生会大彻大悟 痛改前非
Who's talking?
谁在说话？
500 years ago your master Longevity Monk sacrificed
五百年前你师父唐三藏为了赎你一命
his life to save you
牺牲了他自己
Heaven Emperor planned that
玉皇大帝特意安排你
you revive after 500 years
五百年后重投人间
I hope you'll be like your master
希望你能学你师父一样
Making sacrifices to save the others
舍己为人
To clean the sin that you've made before
把你过去的一切罪孽洗清
You should put on the Gold Ring on your head
只要你肯自愿带上金刚圈
Admit you sin
肯改过自新
Then you'll become the super Monkey King
你就可以变回法力无边的齐天大圣
You'll take the responsibility to get scriptures in the west
到时候你就要负起取西经的重任
Rewrite the history
把历史重改
All things in human life is then none of your business
不过从此人间一切与你无关
you can't have any desires anymore
再不能有半点情欲 半点留恋
Worship Buddha whole-heartedly
要全心皈依我佛
You haven't turned into the Monkey King
你还没变成真正的孙悟空托世
because you haven't met the guy
只是因为你还没有遇上
who gives you the 3 birthmarks
那个给你三颗痣的人
After you see him
当你遇上她之后
your whole life will be changed
你的一生就会改变
Talking to me?
跟我说话吗？
I don't think so
不是跟我说的吧？
I think you have made a mistake
认错人啦
Crazy!
秀逗哦！
Painful...
没事啦！  好痛呀…
Let go!
放手呀
Keep calm please No
你镇静点行不行啊？         不行…
Keep calm
镇静！安静！
I'm painful
哎呀！好痛啊
I'm painful, too
我也一样痛啊！
Mind the traps here
小心机关
Chase
追
Go!
走呀
Come her and grab me
快拉住我呀
Ok, do it...Ok! It's coming
抓住了… 生了…
The Longevity Monk was born go to get him!
唐三藏出世了 快找
Yes!
是！
The baby looks like you
是男的 长得很像你诶！
I think
我觉得
being an immortal or not is not important
做不做神仙
The flesh of the Longevity Monk isn't must, too
能不能吃到唐僧肉并不重要
We have to live together happily
最重要的是我们以后能好好的生活
Bring our son up
把孩大带大
Don't let him be robber
不要像我一样当山贼
You want the Longevity Monk most
你那么想要唐僧
Just call him Longevity
干脆儿子就叫做三藏好了
Who?
谁？
It is too coincident
我们可算是冤家路窄
What do you want?
你想怎么样？
Your baby?
孩子是你的？
My baby with Joker!
没错 是我跟至尊宝生的
What are you talking about?
你说什么？
Maiden, tell him
奶妈 你告诉她吧！
Tell him!
你说呀！
Yes!
是！
this is her baby with Joker
她跟至尊宝生的
Go!
走
See where you can go
看你往哪跑？
No need to scare, I'm gonna protect you
不要怕 我保护你
Who the hell you are?
你是哪块蒜苗？
You're not qualified to protect me
凭什么保护我？
Get lost
滚开
take my son away
把儿子抱走
Come here!
过来呀！
Give me the Longevity Monk
把唐三藏给我
I'm not calling you to come
我不是让你过来啊
This is my son
这是我儿子啊
not the Longevity Monk
不是唐三藏
Help!
救命呀…
You're concerned about me I'll die for you
你这么关心我 我愿意为你精尽人亡
Take my son away
带我儿子走！
Don't go!
不走
Go
走
Ma'am 30th
三十娘
It is lucky that we can go out
总算跑出来了
Jing Jing
晶晶
Honey
老婆
Tortoise Magic
龟缩大法
Slash your liver, stomach
我割你的肝！割你的胃！
and internal organs!
我割你的心脏！割你的肺！
Tie it with a knot
打个蝴蝶结
Here comes the spirit
元神出窍
Bitch, don't step on my intestine
贱人！别再踩我的肠子啦
I wanna do so
喜欢！高兴！爱！
Honey...!
老婆…！
My wife is inside
我老婆在里面
Please help me!
拜托你帮帮忙啊！
I'm not free
没有空！
Thanks!
拜托啦！
Come out!
出来啦！
Go!
走
Can we go back to the past?
是不是真的能时光倒流？
Hurry up! Go!
快走 走！
I won't! Let's go together
我不走！要走一起走！
Listen to me
你听我说
Bring up my son
好好带大我们的孩子
Go!
走呀！
Our son! Honey!
我们的孩子！娘子！
you have to leave or I'll die!
你再不走我就死给你看
No!
不要啊！
Honey...Honey...
娘子…
Honey!
相公！
the moon is rising!
月光快出来！
Honey
娘子
Ok!
好！
What's that? I've forgot that!
波罗什么玩意忘光光了
Boyi Bolomi...
般若波罗蜜！
Being immortal!
升仙了！
Great! We're going back to the past
帅呀！真的时光倒流了！
Wait for me!
等等…
The killer is leaving
凶手跑得那么快？再来！
Honey...My wife
老婆…我老婆
Your wife is coming out, easy!
你老婆就快出来了 你急什么？
I've not finished. How do you know?
我还没说完 你是怎么知道的？
She's coming out. Go!
真的出来了         走呀
Honey, honey...
娘子…
Boyi Bolomi!
般若波罗蜜！
Being immortal again!
又升仙了！
Why did you say again?
为什么要说“又”呢？
Wait...
等等…！
Again!
再来！
Honey...!
老婆…！
Don't disturb me!
我警告你别烦我！
Why did you tell me not to disturb you?
为什么要我别烦你？还要警告我呢？
Shit! You're annoying!
你真是啰嗦啊
I know I'm annoying
是啊！我也觉得自己很啰嗦
Why?
为什么？
You come out!
出来啦！
Go, go!
走 走哇！
Honey...
娘子…
Boyi Bolomi
般若波罗蜜…
You're also very annoying
我靠 又要升了
Wait...
等等…
Damn, I'm very tired
我的妈呀 累死我了
Honey...
老婆…
Give me
拿来
I won't tell you!
我懒得跟你说！
That's fine
懒得跟我说就不要说嘛
Why did you do so?
为什么要打我呢？
Honey...
娘子…
Boyi Bolomi...
般若波罗蜜…
Honey, come out with King Bull and see Jesus
娘子呀 跟牛魔王出来看上帝
Stop!
刀下留人！
Commit suicide
原来是自杀
Why commit suicide?
你为什么要自杀呢？
No, I prefer killing you!
自杀？要死也先杀了你
Hero!
英雄！
You let me go!
你放过我吧
Let you go?
放过你？
Tell me a reason why I have to let you go
你给我一个不杀你的理由
You tell me a reason why you wanna kill me
正在想！你给我一个杀我的理由先
Ok, you leave me alone
好哇！你一声不响丢下我
and you have a baby with my sister
还跟师姐生了个儿子！
No, that's not the case Wanna die?
你完全误会了         找死？
No, hero!
不要啊 英雄！
I left because I wanna get medication for you from you sister
我是回来跟你师姐拿解药去救你的
But I was late
谁知道晚了一步
I couldn't find you
回去已经找不到你了
You deceive me!
你骗我
You don't trust me
你不信
You look
你看
Where have they been?
他们到哪儿去了？
What's up?
怎么啦？
You can't leave!
你跑不掉的！
When the rock is put down the door is closed
断龙石关了就打不开了 快出去！
Honey...
娘子…
Let me do this
让我来！
Go!
走哇！
Joker, see you in the next life
至尊宝来世再见
Honey
娘子…
Honey!
相公…
Again!
再来！
Boyi Bolomi...
般若波罗蜜…
Jing Jing
晶晶！
Where are they?
人呢？都到哪儿去了？
What's going on?
怎么会这样呢？
Immortal?
神仙？
Devil?
妖怪？
Thanks!
谢谢！
Don't go into the Spider Web Cave!
盘丝洞不要乱闯！
Spider Web Cave?
盘丝洞？
You think I'm illiterate?
你当我不识字呀？
Waterfall Cave
明明是水帘洞嘛！
Spider Web Cave. It is a good name
盘丝洞这个名字也蛮好听的
Spider Web Cave
盘丝洞
We'll live here onwards
以后我住在这儿
Stop!
等一等！
I wanna announce
我现在郑重宣布
In this hill, all things belong to me
这个山所有东西都是属于我的
Including you
包括你在内
Me?
我？
yes
对呀
you look like a donkey let me make a mark on you
就像我的骡子一样给你盖个章！
You're mine now
你现在是我的人了
If someone bully you you tell them you know me
如果有人欺负你呢 就报我的名字
I'm called Spider Web Immortal now!
从今天起 我叫盘丝大仙
Spider Web Immortal?
盘丝大仙？
500 years?
五百年前？
You haven't turned into Monkey King
你没有变成孙悟空托世
because you haven't met the guy having three birthmarks
是因为你还没碰到给你三颗痣的人
Close the door
芝麻关门！